dit.ie 2019-05-28

# Cookie Policy | TU Dublin - Technological University Dublin

**Using Our Website & Cookie Policy**

This Cookie Policy relates to [www.dit.ie](https://www.dit.ie/)

## What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file that may be stored on your computer or mobile device that contains data related to a website you visit. It may allow a website “remember” your actions or preferences over a period of time, or it may contain data related to the function or delivery of the site. Cookies can be set by the owner of the website or in some cases by third party services the website owner allows to present other information, run content or provide other functionality such as analytics.

Further information on cookies can be found at: <http://ec.europa.eu/ipg/basics/legal/cookies/index_en.htm>

## How are they used on this site?

[www.dit.ie](https://www.dit.ie/) uses cookies only for functionality that is strictly necessary for services that are explicitly requested by the user for their session as per Regulation 5(5), SI 336 of 2011 (the ePrivacy Regulations).  This website uses session cookies. Session cookies are used to deliver the basic functions of a website i.e. to allow pages to remember technical changes or selections you may make between pages. Session cookies are temporary cookies and are generally erased when you close your browser.

## Managing Cookies

Within your browser you can choose whether you wish to accept cookies or not. Different browsers make different controls available to you and so we provide links below to popular manufacturers' instructions on how you can do this. Generally, your browser will offer you the choice to accept, refuse or delete cookies at all times, or those from providers that website owners use ("third party cookies"), or those from specific websites.

This Cookie Policy forms part of our overall Privacy Statement

## The First-party cookies we use on dit.ie are:

We use a service called Google Analytics to collect data about the number of visits to pages of our site, and the journey of visitors through the site. This helps us to optimise the site design. The Google Analytics cookies used on our site are listed in the table below.

## List of First-party cookies on this site and their purpose:

Cookie name| Purpose  
---|---  
  
AWSALB

| 

We use Amazon Web Services to host our system. This cookie allows us to deliver our service seamlessly from multiple services using a load balancer, so the cookie simply recordsd which server cluster is serving you.  
  
__utma

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
__utmb

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
__utmc

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
__utmt

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
__utmz

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
_ga

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
_gcl_au

| 

Cookie used for Google Analytics.  
  
lang

| 

We use a session cookie to remember your language preference when viewing the site. This session cookie (called lang) is erased when you close your browser or after 5 minutes of inactivity.  
  
CONSENT

| 

This cookie allows the website to “remember” your actions or preferences regarding the use of cookies on the website.  
  
## Collection and use of personal information

TU Dublin fully respects the rights of users of our website and is committed to protecting your privacy rights. TU Dublin will not collect any personal information (personal data) about you on this website without your permission and any information which you volunteer to TU Dublin will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality and processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1988 and Data Protection (Amendment) Act 2003.

## Cookies and collection and use of technical information

Information on internet traffic is collected routinely by TU Dublin and by its service providers (eg, HEAnet). This technical information is used to ensure the smooth running of the TU Dublin computer network and for statistical or administrative purposes.  It is _not_ used to gather identifiable personal information on individual website visitors, except in so far as this is permitted by law and may be necessary in order to prevent or detect problems or offences in relation to the operation of the website.

This information may be used for the purposes of evaluating your use of the TU Dublin website and to improve our website service to you. It is stored and used in the aggregate only and is not used to obtain personal data or to contact you personally.

## What are cookies?

A cookie is a small text file that a website can store on your computer to help keep track of different things, like if you want to stay logged into a website, or your preferences within a website. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Cookies may be persistent, they may expire after some predefined period of time, or they may expire at a given date in the future. When a user visits the same website again, the browser may send cookies back to that website allowing the website to recognise the user and remember things like their personalised details or preferences.

A website may use a third party advertising network to deliver targeted advertising on their website, which may also have the capability to track your browsing activity across different sites. This website does not use this type of cookie.

## Session cookies

Session cookies are stored temporarily during a browsing session and are deleted from the user’s device when the browser is closed.

## Persistent cookies

This type of cookie is saved on your computer for a fixed period and is not deleted when the browser is closed.

## How cookies are being used

TU Dublin uses cookies to help improve your experience on our site and to help us understand what content is most useful to our visitors

  * TU Dublin cookies are used only by TU Dublin related systems.
  * Certain cookies are essential to the proper functioning of TU Dublin systems.
  * We use analytics cookies to help us understand what content is most useful to our visitors.
  * Cookies are not used by this website to store any personal information. 
  * We use some session cookies to make navigation through the website smoother.  These are automatically deleted after you close your web browser
  * We use persistent cookies when we need to manage return visits. For example, we use this type of cookie to know how many repeat visits the site receives compared with new visits.
  * IP addresses are read by the website to identify users located on the TU Dublin campus in order to offer them internal functionality. 

## Types of cookies we use

  * Security: These cookies allow us to secure access to your account, and to allow you to move between TU Dublin systems without additional authentication.
  * Google Analytics (_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz): These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. More Information 

## Third party cookies

Our site, like most websites, includes functionality provided by third parties. A common example is an embedded YouTube video or an embedded google map

For example when you visit a page with content embedded from, Google, Twitter, YouTube  or Facebook, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browser. For example, Facebook sets cookies via our website if you ‘like’ one of the posts on our site and twitter sets cookies via our website if you “tweet” one of the posts on our site.

Google Custom Search Engine (CSE) functionality has been implemented on the website for the in-page search box. The Google CSE may deliver cookies. The CSE is covered by the Google Privacy Policy. <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

We embed videos from YouTube across our site. When you watch these videos on our website, YouTube may store cookies used for a range of purposes. For more information, visit [YouTube/Google Privacy information](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=uk)

As these are third party providers, we do not control the use of these cookies and cannot access them. You should check the third party websites for more information about these cookies.

Disabling these cookies will likely break the functions offered by these third parties

## List of third party cookies on this site, their purpose and name:

Domain| Purpose| Cookie name  
---|---|---  
  
addthis.com

| 

Social media sharing buttons.

| 

Xtc, uid, _atuvc, uit, dt, _atrfs, loc, ssh, sshs, ssc  
  
doubleclick.net

| 

Measure the effectivenes of advertising

| 

IDE, test_cookie  
  
facebook.com

| 

Social media sharing buttons.

| 

lu, datr, presence, act, p, sub, c_user, s, xs, csm  
  
google.com

| 

1P_JAR: Google cookie that carries out information about how the end user uses the website and any advertising that the end user may have seen before visiting the website.

testcookie: Used to test if the browser suports displaying of the cookie statement at the top of the browser window.

| 

testcookie, 1P_JAR  
  
twitter.com

| 

Display DIT twitter streams & social media sharing.

| 

_twitter_sess, guest_id, k, remember_checked, twid, twll, original_referrer, external_referer  
  
youtube.com

| 

Display of content hosted on youtube.com

| 

VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, YSC,GPS  
  
scorecardresearch.com

| 

Part of the slideshare.net powerpoint presentation display.

| 

UID, UIDR  
  
Sharethis.com

| 

Sharing buttons on website.

| 

__stid, __uset  
  
Donate.dit. mycharity.ie

| 

Embedded Online donations widget via mycharity.

| 

PHPSESSID  
  
Google Search Console

| 

A browser sends this cookie with requests to Google’s sites. The NID cookie contains a unique ID Google uses to remember your preferences and other information, such as your preferred language (e.g. English), how many search results you wish to have shown per page, and whether or not you wish to have Google’s SafeSearch turned on.

| 

PHPSESSID  
  
## Web Browsing

By simply visiting our website, you do not disclose, nor do we collect, personal data about you. The information collected about your visit is limited to technical data such as:

  1. the Internet address (or IP address) of the device you used to access this website
  2. whether you reached the site using a search engine or if you clicked a link on another website
  3. the type of web-browser you used
  4. the type of device you used to access the Internet.

We use this data for administrative and statistical purposes as well as to help us improve our website. This technical data does not provide us with the personal data of visitors to our website.

## Your Rights

Pursuant to the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003, you have a right to obtain a copy of the data held about you for a fee.  Also, if incorrect information is held about you, you have a right to request that this information is amended or erased.  Further information on your rights under the Data Protection legislation is available [here](https://www.dit.ie/institutesecretarysoffice/informationgovernance/dataprotectionincludingrecordsmanagement/). 

This statement should not be construed as a contractual undertaking.  The Institute reserves the right to review and amend this statement at any time without notice and you should therefore re-visit this webpage from time to time.

Any queries or concerns you may have about the processing of personal information on this website should be addressed to:

Records Manager  
TU Dublin  
143-149 Lower Rathmines Road  
Dublin 6

**E-mail** : [foi@dit.ie](mailto:foi@dit.ie)   
**Tel** : +353-1-402 7519
